<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Environmental Surveillance Monitoring</string>

    <string name="mq1_text">The MQ137 is a gas sensor designed to detect ammonia (NH₃) gas concentrations in the air. It belongs to the MQ series of gas sensors, which are widely used for detecting various gases. The MQ137 sensor can detect ammonia concentrations in the range of 5 ppm to 500 ppm (parts per million), making it useful for applications in industries like agriculture, chemical manufacturing, and environmental monitoring. you can test the MQ137 sensors functionality and use it for ammonia detection in your project. The sensor will provide different analog readings depending on the ammonia concentration. However you will need to calibrate the sensor in a controlled environment to get accurate PPM readings</string>
    <string name="mq2_text">The MQ2 sensor is a versatile gas sensor used to detect various gases such as LPG (Liquefied Petroleum Gas), butane, propane, methane, alcohol, hydrogen, and smoke. It’s widely used in safety systems, gas leakage detectors, and fire alarm systems due to its sensitivity to a wide range of gases. The sensor operates by using a tin dioxide (SnO₂) semiconductor layer that changes its resistance in the presence of gases. Place the sensor near a gas source (e.g., a lighter but without igniting the flame) and observe the readings. The analog value should increase in the presence of gas.</string>
    <string name="mq3_text">The MQ3 sensor is a gas sensor commonly used to detect alcohol, making it useful in breathalyzers or systems designed to measure blood alcohol content. It can also be used to detect other gases like benzene, methane, propane, and more, though its sensitivity is particularly high for alcohol. Using in Breath analyzers, safety monitoring systems, alcohol detectors in automobiles, etc. The detection happens due to the changes in resistance when alcohol is detected, which is then converted into an electrical signal.</string>
    <string name="mq4_text">The MQ-4 sensor is a gas sensor designed to detect methane (CH₄) and other natural gases like propane and butane. Its widely used in applications like gas leak detection, air quality monitoring, and safety devices. The sensor works by using a heated tin dioxide (SnO₂) semiconductor layer, which changes its resistance when it comes into contact with certain gases. This change in resistance is used to measure the concentration of the gas.</string>
    <string name="mq5_text">The MQ5 sensor is a gas sensor commonly used to detect the presence of natural gases like LPG (Liquefied Petroleum Gas), methane, and hydrogen. It is often used in gas leakage detection systems and other safety monitoring devices. Bring a gas source (like a lighter or LPG sample) close to the sensor to see if the values change.</string>
    <string name="mq6_text">The MQ6 sensor is a type of gas sensor that detects the presence of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), butane, propane, and methane. Its commonly used in gas leak detection systems for homes, industries, and vehicles. The MQ6 sensor operates by sensing gas concentrations in the air and outputs an analog signal corresponding to the gas concentration level. Detects concentrations of LPG, propane, butane, and methane between 300 ppm (parts per million) to 10,000 ppm.</string>

    <string name="humidity_text">A Humidity and Temperature sensor is an electronic device used to measure the ambient temperature and the relative humidity in the air. These sensors are widely used in weather monitoring, indoor climate control, agriculture, and industrial applications. You can test these sensors by connecting them to a microcontroller (like Arduino, ESP8266, or Raspberry Pi) and writing a program to read the sensor data.A Humidity and Temperature sensor is an electronic device used to measure the ambient temperature and the relative humidity in the air. These sensors are widely used in weather monitoring, indoor climate control, agriculture, and industrial applications. You can test these sensors by connecting them to a microcontroller (like Arduino, ESP8266, or Raspberry Pi) and writing a program to read the sensor data.</string>
</resources>